in linkedin://amiraliameri

github://amiraliamhh

stackoverflow://amirali-ameri

Self-taught full-stack developer with over 4 years of experience in developing enterprise applications. Expert in **Javascript** and its ecosystem; focused on the entire pipeline of delivering a product, from taking an initial concept to deployment; full-time learner with a fundamental awareness of data structures and algorithms. Specialized in developing SPA and PWA.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Full-Stack Developer**

Legamart - 2020-10 / present - contract

- Worked with Product and UI/UX teams to develop Case-Review microservice of Legamart which helps customers with assessing their legal cases.
- Contributing to the development of the front-end using React and MaterialUI as our main stack. (WIP)

## **Full-Stack Developer**

Jabama - 2019-09 / present - full-time

- Contributed to developing the back-end of the search engine of Jabama using Node, Nestjs, Elasticsearch, etc.
- Developed the Referral system of Jabama.
- Contributed to migrating legacy monolith codebase to a microservices codebase.
- Leading a team of 4 to develop the front-end of the redesigned Jabama website, mobile PWA, and admin panel using Vue, Typescript, and Nuxt.is for **SSR**. (WIP)

## **Front-End Developer**

Jabama - 2019-05 / 2019-09 - full-time

- Communicated and worked closely with the Marketing and SEO teams to add analytical tools (Google Analytics/Hotjar) to the web application.
- Worked closely with Product, UI/UX, Back-end, and QA teams to develop a redesigned version of the Product Details Page, leading to a 1.5% increase in conversion rate.
- Maintained legacy codebase and contributed to fixing critical bugs.

#### **Front-End Developer**

Arta Sarmayeh - 2018-12 / 2019-06 - full-time

- Worked closely with all of the teams in the company to deliver a
  pixel-perfect and fully functional web application to help stock
  traders maximize their gains.
- Developed and maintained e2e and unit tests with over 90% code coverage using Jest and Cypress.

# **Open-Source Projects**

#### GoStreestTest

github.com/arashrasoulzadeh/GoStreestTest

A tool for stress testing REST endpoints. Written in Go programming language.

#### Jabama/vue-carousel

github.com/jabama-co/vue-carousel

Cloned from the popular vue-carousel repo, with some additional features such as vertical carousel and nested carousels included.

#### **Nuxt-dto**

github.com/farnabaz/nuxt-dto

Nuxt-dto is a Nuxt.js module developed to ease the communication with REST APIs, especially when your product still is in MVP stage and breaking changes to endpoints are inevitable.

## **Technical Skills**

#### **Expert**

ES6-ES2020, Typescript, React, Redux, Vue, Nuxtjs, Node, Express, Nestjs, Websocket, Web Workers, Jest, HTML, CSS, SCSS, MongoDB, Redis, Bootstrap

#### Intermediate

Go, Elasticsearch, Nginx, RabbitMQ, Storybook, CSS-in-JS, Angular +5, Cypress, Git

#### **Novice**

Elixir, PHP, Python, Django, Nextjs, GraphQL, MySQL, Posrgresql, Angularjs, Webpack

#### **Personal Skills**

- Having Leadership Qualities.
- Ability to work under pressure.

# Amirali Heidari

+989190912275

amiraliamhh@gmail.com

in linkedin://amiraliameri

github://amiraliamhh

🖹 stackoverflow://amirali-ameri

## **EXPERIENCE**

## **Full-Stack Developer**

Bitooman - 2018-01 / 2018-12 - full-time

- Used Node, Express, Typescript, Angular, and React to develop a fully functioning cryptocurrency exchange platform.
- Developed admin panel of Bitooman which helps people analyze crypto-market using live (websocket) cryptocurrency statistics and charts.
- Worked on internal tools for the Marketing team to assist them in acquiring more users for the platform.

## **Education**

Self Educated

## Languages

English (Professional working proficiency)

Farsi (Native Proficiency)

## **Front-End Developer**

IranCIP - 2017-08 / 2017-10 - contract

 Used Angular 2 and Ionic to develop the Android application of IranCIP.